Finding aid to Record Group 9. Photographs, of the YWCA of the U.S.A. records SSC.MS.00324.RG9
Sophia Smith Collection
- Prints and negatives, 1
  - International Work, D
    - Burma, circa 1923-1962 (Box 1003, Folder 7)
      Myanmar; Young Women's Christian associations -- Burma; Women -- International cooperation; Leadership in women; Women -- Burma; Youth -- Burma; Teenage girls -- Burma; Women -- Religious life -- Burma
    - Cameroon, 1964 (Box 1003, Folder 8)
      Photograph of Peace Corps volunteers assisting with adjustments to a corn mill. The volunteers in the picture are part of a collaborative project between the Cameroon government, the United Natioans Technical Assistance Programs and the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO).
      Women -- International cooperation; Leadership in women; Women -- Cameroon; Women in development--International cooperation; Cameroon; Peace Corps (U.S.); Unesco; United Nations. Technical Assistance Administration
    - Caribbean, 1967-1972 (Box 1003, Folder 9)
      Photographs of a YWCA building in St. Vincent and of the YWCA Caribbean Area Conference in Leonsberg.
      Caribbean Area; Women--International cooperation; Leadership in women; Women -- Caribbean Area; Congresses and conventions -- Caribbean Area; Young Women's Christian associations -- Caribbean Area
    - Chile: Buildings, 1956-1990 (Box 1003, Folder 10)
      Photographs of the interiors and exteriors of young women's Christian association buildings in Chile. Some photographs depict buildings and facilities in use.
      Women -- International cooperation; Women -- Chile; Young Women's Christian associations -- Chile; Chile
    - Chile: Camping, circa 1929-1967 (Box 1003, Folder 11)
      Photographs of YWCA Camp Olmué in Valparaiso, Chile. The young women's Christian association in Chile uses the camp to host day camp programs, overnights and a special experimental camp for handicapped children. Photographs show campers swimming, hiking, making crafts, socializing and participating in other outdoor recreation.
      Women -- International cooperation; Leadership in women; Women -- Chile; Young Women's Christian associations -- Chile; Youth -- Chile; Camp sites, facilities, etc. -- Chile; Camps for Children with disabilities -- Chile; Children with disabilities -- Chile; Chile
    - Chile: Children, circa 1959-1979 (Box 1004, Folder 1)
      Photographs of programs for children in young women's Christian associations in Chile. These programs include preschools, kindergartens and day care in addition to family services and recreation opportunities for local children.
      Women -- International cooperation; Leadership in women; Women -- Chile; Young Women's Christian associations -- Chile; Youth -- Chile; Children with disabilities -- Chile; Child care services -- Chile; Chile
    - Chile: Health, circa 1960-1969 (Box 1004, Folder 2)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association health programs, classes and services for children and families in Chile. Photographed activities include health education classes, child and infant care classes and services for handicapped children.
      Women--International cooperation; Leadership in women; Women -- Chile; Youth -- Chile; Young Women's Christian associations -- Chile; Children with disabilities -- Chile; Child care services -- Chile; Health education -- Chile; Chile
    - Chile: Mothers' Club, 1960-1967 (Box 1004, Folder 3)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association mothers' clubs in Chile. These clubs provide skills training, social activities and community projects for mothers of young children.
      Women -- International cooperation; Leadership in women; Women -- Chile; Young Women's Christian associations -- Chile; Children -- Chile; Mothers -- Chile; Chile
    - Chile: Peace Corps Chile project, 1962-1963 (Box 1004, Folder 4-5)
      Photographs of YWCA Peace Corps projects in Chile. In the early 1960's the YWCA of the USA developed international projects in partnership with the Peace Corps. Volunteers in Chile worked mainly with children and youth in camps, housing projects, kindergartens and a hospital for disabled children. YWCA Peace Corps volunteers are identified on the backs of most photographs. Following the photographs of program activities are photographs of "Peace Corps paintings." These materials are followed by a mounted series of photographs highlighting the work of volunteers in Chile likely prepared for a presentation or exhibit.
      Women -- International cooperation; Leadership in women; Young Women's Christian associations -- Chile; Children -- Chile; Women in development--International cooperation; Volunteers -- Chile; Chile; Peace Corps (U.S.)
    - Chile: Physical education and recreation, circa 1947-1957 (Box 1004, Folder 6)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association physical education classes and recreation programs. Physical education and gym classes include swimming, dance and "slimnastics" while recreation activities include co-ed picnics, singing and folkdance.
      Women--International cooperation; Leadership in women; Young Women's Christian associations -- Chile; Children -- Chile; Volunteers -- Chile; Women in development -- International cooperation; Outdoor recreation -- Chile; Physical education for women -- Chile; Women -- Chile; Chile
    - Chile: Program, 1947-1967 (Box 1004, Folder 7)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association program activities in Chile. Photographs feature program activities such as sewing classes, mother's clubs, music classes, social events, celebrations, cooking classes and a fundraising campaign.
      Women -- International cooperation; Leadership in women; Young Women's Christian associations -- Chile; Children -- Chile; Volunteers -- Chile; Women in development--International cooperation; Adult education of women -- Chile; Fund raising -- Chile; Christmas -- Chile; Special events -- Chile
    - Chile: Staff and volunteers, circa 1960-1982 (Box 1004, Folder 8)
      Photographs of staff and volunteers participating in and leading activities for young women's Christian associations in Chile. Many staff and volunteers are identified on the backs of the photographs.
      Women -- International cooperation; Leadership in women; Young Women's Christian associations -- Chile; Volunteers -- Chile; Women in development--International cooperation; Special events -- Chile; Chile
    - Chile: Y-Teens, circa 1950-1964 (Box 1004, Folder 9)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association programs and clubs for teenaged girls in Chile. Y-Teen programs, or clubs for teenage members, include cooking and craft classes, social activities and community engagement.
      Women -- International cooperation; Leadership in women; Young Women's Christian associations -- Chile; Volunteers -- Chile; Special events -- Chile; Women in development -- International cooperation; Teenage girls -- Societies and clubs -- Chile; Chile
    - China: Buildings, circa 1913-1944 (Box 1004, Folder 10)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association buildings, hostess houses, recreation facilities and residences in China.
      Young Women's Christian Associations -- China; Women in development--International cooperation; Housing -- China; Women -- China; China; Zhonghua Jidu jiao nü qing nian hui; Zhonghua Jidu jiao nü qing nian hui -- Buildings
    - China: Celebrations, ceremonies and pageants, circa 1919-1926 (Box 1004, Folder 11)
      Photographs of celebrations, ceremonies and pageants of the young women's Christian associations in China. These special activities are part of the YWCA program and they highlight local customs, share international traditions and celebrate the life and people of the young women's Christian associations in China. Included are photographs of Christmas decorations, a halloween party, pageants, plays and a YWCA secretary's wedding photograph.
      Young Women's Christian Associations -- China; Women in development -- International cooperation; Housing -- China; Women -- China; China; Zhonghua Jidu jiao nü qing nian hui
    - China: Children, circa 1922-1929, 1963 (Box 1005, Folder 1)
      Photographs of children participating in young women's Christian association programs in China and individual and group snapshots of children. YWCA programs for children in China include providing essentail care, classes and skills training, recreational opportunities and child care services.
      Young Women's Christian Associations -- China; Women in development--International cooperation; Children -- China; Refugees -- China; Rural children -- China; Child care services -- China; China; Zhonghua Jidu jiao nü qing nian hui
    - China: Classes, circa 1924-1971 (Box 1005, Folder 2)
      Photographs of young women's Chrisitan association classes in China. The YWCA education program in China includes evening classes for girls and young women working in industry, classes for young children, adult literacy classes and english language classes. Photographs include images of classes in session, instructors and groups of students.
      China; Young Women's Christian Associations -- China; Women in development -- International cooperation; Children -- China; Rural children -- China; Education -- China; Adult education -- China; Women -- Employment -- China; Youth -- China; Literacy -- China; Leadership in women; Zhonghua Jidu jiao nü qing nian hui
    - China: Conferences, circa 1907-1947 (Box 1005, Folder 3)
      Similar to the YWCA of the USA, young women's Christian associations in China hold regional and national conferences to meet other women, unite under shared purpose, develop leadership skills and discuss issues affecting the women of China and women around the world. Photographs include group portraits and images of conference sessions for industrial, student, regional and national. Also included are several photographs of staff meetings, board meetings and World YWCA conference delegates.
      China; Young Women's Christian Associations -- China; Congresses and conventions -- China; Women -- China; Leadership in women; Forums (Discussion and debate) -- China; Zhonghua Jidu jiao nü qing nian hui
    - China: Dramatics, circa 1922-1933 (Box 1005, Folder 4)
      Young women's Christian associations in China use plays, pageants and music performances for recreation, entertainment and cultural education. In these photographs young tobacco workers, Girl reserves and other YWCA members demonstrate folk dances and participate in plays such as Mu-Lan and Sleeping Beauty. Also included are images of a music performance, a puppet show and may pole festivities.
      China; Young Women's Christian Associations -- China; Leadership in women; Youth -- China; Pageants -- China; Theater -- China; Zhonghua Jidu jiao nü qing nian hui
    - China: Education and recreation, circa 1920-163 (Box 1005, Folder 5)
      China; Young Women's Christian Associations -- China; Women -- China; Leadership in women; Youth -- China; Students -- China; Education -- China; Recreation -- China; Zhonghua Jidu jiao nü qing nian hui
    - China: Health and nutrition, Circa 1930-1950 (Box 1005, Folder 6)
      As a result of war and food shortages in China local children and adults are in need of food assistance and community health services. The young women's Christian associations in China help fill the needs by organizing milk stations for daily supplemental nutrition, community meals, nursery care for young children of working mothers and family health services. Photographs include images of children drinking their milk rations, community service proejcts and a photograph of university students at a milk bar.
      China; Young Women's Christian Associations -- China; Women -- China; Leadership in women; Youth -- China; War relief -- China; Students -- China; Basic needs -- China; Zhonghua Jidu jiao nü qing nian hui
    - China: Hostels, circa 1940-1949 (Box 1005, Folder 7)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association hostels in China. Hostels provide inexpensive food and lodging for employed women in China who may need access to safe and affordable rooms. The need for such accomodations is high and one photographer's caption notes that the number of girls on the waiting list for the hostel is in the hundreds. Photographs show hostel guests in their rooms and community areas.
      China; Young Women's Christian Associations -- China; Leadership in women; Basic needs -- China; Women -- Employment -- China; Tourist camps, hostels, etc. -- China; Housing -- China; Zhonghua Jidu jiao nü qing nian hui
    - China: Industrial, circa 1907-1941 (Box 1005, Folder 8)
      Photographs of the industrial program of young women's Christian associations in China. The industrial programs offer classes, recreation and social opportunities for women employed in idustries such as textiles and tabacco. For unemployed women, industrial centers are a place to develop skills and interact with others in similar situations and in rural areas, the industrial programs help groups of women establish cooperative cotton and wool productions. The photographs include women at work, groups of industrial YWCA members and an unidentified labor parade. Also included are two images of labor posters.
      Young Women's Christian Associations -- China; Women -- China; Leadership in women; Basic needs -- China; Women -- Employment -- China; Textile industry -- China; Tobacco industry -- China; Women in the labor movement -- China; Zhonghua Jidu jiao nü qing nian hui
    - China: Miscellaneous, circa 1915-1948; 1986 (Box 1005, Folder 9)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association members and activiites in China. Young women's Christian associations in China serve its women and girls through clubs, education programs and community services. During times of war, the YWCAbecome vital hubs for communities. The YWCA war services and the effect of the war on its community is documented and described in an unbound scrapbook. In addition, there are photographs of scenes of Chinese communities and YWCA activities.
      China; Young Women's Christian Associations -- China; Leadership in women; Children -- China; Youth -- China; War relief -- China; Zhonghua Jidu jiao nü qing nian hui
    - China: Negatives (Box 1005, Folder 10)
    - China: Physical education, circa 1915-1932 (Box 1005, Folder 11)
      Photographs of physical education programs at young women's Christian associations in China. These programs include athletics such as track and field, gymnasium classes and outdoor recreation. In addition, the YWCA in China operates a training school for physical education that trains leaders in the field. Photographs include images of physical education classes, college athletics and classes of the national training schools.
      China; Young Women's Christian Associations -- China; Leadership in women; Physical education and training -- China; Physical education for women -- China; Women athletes -- China; Zhonghua Jidu jiao nü qing nian hui
    - China: Refugees and family sufferers, circa 1928-1939 (Box 1006, Folder 1)
      Photographs of young women's Christian associations programs for refugees and family sufferers in China. During times of war, conflict and famine, young women's Christian associations provided aid and support to refugees and famine sufferers, especially in rural areas. Photographs document those affected by such conditions, residents in refugee camps and rural programs.
      China; Young Women's Christian Associations -- China; War relief -- China; Refugees -- China; Rural children -- China; Food relief -- China; Victims of famine -- China; Zhonghua Jidu jiao nü qing nian hui
    - China: Rural work, circa 1940-1949 (Box 1006, Folder 2)
      Volunteers from young women's Christian associations in China dedicate time to bringing programs to rural communities that would otherwise not be reached. Photographs include a group portrait of these volunteers as well as scenes of rural life in China.
      China; Young Women's Christian Associations -- China; Rural children -- China; Rural women -- China; Agriculture -- China; Volunteers -- China; Women in development--International cooperation; Zhonghua Jidu jiao nü qing nian hui
    - China: Scenes, circa 1912-1949 (Box 1006, Folder 3)
      Scenes of rural and city life in China including images of people, buildings and landmarks. Most photographs are not of YWCA activity but are instead of scenes of daily life in China.
      China; Postcards; Young Women's Christian Associations -- China; Zhonghua Jidu jiao nü qing nian hui
    - China: School of Physical Education, Shaghai, 1923 (3 photos); Hangchow: graduation exercises, 1923-24; YWCA membership party, 1925 (Box 1049, Folder 4)
    - China: Snapshots from Ella Bennett, circa 1934-1940; Bennett, Ella (Box 1006, Folder 4)
      Photographs taken by Ella Bennett, a YWCA of the USA representative working in China. Ms. Bennett documented the work of the young women's Christian associations in China, the people she encountered and the scenes around her. Some photographs have brief descriptions or identifying information but many are unidentified.
      China; Young Women's Christian Associations -- China; Women -- China; Children -- China; Youth -- China; Leadership in women; Women -- International cooperation; Zhonghua Jidu jiao nü qing nian hui
    - China: Staff and volunteer groups, circa 1919-1940 (Box 1006, Folder 5)
      Photographs of local and international staff working with young women's Christian associations in China. Photographs include individual and group portraits as well as photographs of staff meetings and conferences. Also included is a photograph of Madame Chiang Kai Shek remotely delivering an address to the YWCA of the USA convention in Columbus, Ohio.
      China; Young Women's Christian Associations -- China; Women -- China; Leadership in women; Women--International cooperation; Zhonghua Jidu jiao nü qing nian hui; Chiang, May-ling Soong, 1897-2003
    - China: Women at work, undated (Box 1006, Folder 6)
      Photographs of young women at work and taking part in YWCA employment services. Young women's Christian associations in China may offer vocational guidance and classes in typing and job skills.
      China; Young Women's Christian Associations -- China; Women -- China; Leadership in women; Women -- International cooperation; Women -- Employment -- China; Zhonghua Jidu jiao nü qing nian hui
    - Foldable photo displays: China, Esthonia and Latvia, India (2), Near East, South America, 1920s (Box 1052)
    - Chinese bride (Box 1053, Folder 3)
    - In a Chinese cart (Box 1053, Folder 4)
    - Colombia, circa 1965-1971 (Box 1006, Folder 7-8)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association programs, conferences, activities and leaders in Colombia. The programs of the YWCA in Colombia serve women and young girls and include opportunities for learning new skills, community service, community development, recreation, social activities and leadership development training. Many photographs are attributed to taken by Cecilia Correa.
      Colombia; Young Women's Christian associations -- Colombia; Women -- Colombia; Leadership in women; Women -- International cooperation; Youth -- Colombia; Rural women -- Colombia
    - Cuba, circa 1928 (Box 1006, Folder 9)
      Group photographs from young women's Christian associations in Cuba. A note on the photograph's envelope indicates that some photographs may actually be from Argentina as some are duplicated in the Buenos Aires scrapbook.
      Cuba; Young Women's Christian associations -- Cuba; Women -- Cuba; Leadership in women
    - Czech Republic and Slovakia, circa 1919-1950 (Box 1006, Folder 10)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association activities in the Czech Republic and Slovakia. Early activities center around recreation and physical education. After World War II the photographs indicate a change in focus towards war repair and services for people affected by the war. One photograph shows a YWCA building damaged during occupation by Hitler youth. Other photographs include images of community activities, buildings, camp facilities and YWCA participants.
      Czech Republic; Slovakia; Young Women's Christian associations -- Czech Republic; Women -- Czech Republic; Leadership in women; Women -- International cooperation; World War, 1939-1945 -- War work -- Young Women's Christian associations; Recreation -- Czech Republic|; Physical education for women -- Czech Republic; Young Women's Christian associations -- Slovakia; Women -- Slovakia; Recreation -- Slovakia; Physical education for women -- Slovakia
    - Denmark, circa 1981 (Box 1006, Folder 11)
      Photograph from the United Nations Decade for Women conference in Copenhagen, Denmark.
      Denmark; Women -- Denmark; Leadership in women; Women--International cooperation; United Nations
    - Egypt, circa 1940-1967 (Box 1006, Folder 12-13)
      Photographs of young women's Christian associaiton programs and activities in Egypt.YWCA centers and programs in Egypt serve women and girls from the local communities and abroad. During World War II YWCA centers became rest stops and accommodations for servicewomen on furlough. Photographs depict YWCA activities, members, facilities and special projects. Also included are scenes from around Egypt and its local peoples. Negatives are included in the materials but have not been digitized.
      Women -- Egypt; Leadership in women; Women -- International cooperation; Vocational guidance -- Egypt; Literacy -- Egypt; Education -- Egypt; Young Women's Christian associations -- Egypt; World War, 1939-1945 -- War work -- Young Women's Christian associations
    - England, 1963 (Box 1006, Folder 14)
      [see also: Subseries E. Program, War Work: WWI]
      An interior and exterior shot of a young women's Christian association building in London, England.
      Young Women's Christian associations -- England
    - Estonia, circa 1920-1929 (Box 1006, Folder 15)
      Photographs of a young women's Christian association cooking class, leadership training course and summer camp in Estonia.
      Estonia; Young Women's Christian associations -- Estonia; Women -- Estonia; Cooking -- Study and teaching -- Estonia; Congresses and conventions -- Estonia; Camps for girls -- Estonia
    - Ethiopia: General, circa 1959-1971 (Box 1007, Folder 1)
      Photographs of Young women's Christian associations in Ethiopia. YWCA programs and activities provide much needed services for the women and girls in the community such as a vocational training school, classes in gardening, cooking and English, recreation opportunities and childcare. Photographs include images of YWCA buildings and facilities, vocational training school participants, YWCA leaders, special programs, ceremonies and classes.
      Young Women's Christian Associations -- Ethiopia; Ethiopia; Women -- Ethiopia; Cooking -- Study and teaching -- Ethiopia; Leadership in women; Literacy -- Ethiopia; Children -- Ethiopia; Vocational guidance -- Ethiopia; Adult education of women -- Ethiopia; Recreation -- Ethiopia
    - Ethiopia: Negatives (Box 1007, Folder 2-3)
    - Ethiopia: Opening of the Asmara YWCA, 1967 (Box 1007, Folder 4)
      Photographs from the opening of the Asmara YWCA in Ethiopia. The ceremonies and celebrations are attended by Emperor Haile Selassie and photographs show him receiving guests, touring the facilities and participating in inaugural ceremonies.
      Ethiopia; Young Women's Christian Associations -- Ethiopia; Women -- Ethiopia; Special events -- Ethiopia; Haile Selassie I, Emperor of Ethiopia, 1892-1975
    - Ethiopia: Vocational training, circa 1960-1971 (Box 1007, Folder 5)